WEI YE (WAYNE)

FULL STACK DEVELOPER/TECH LEAD

Website: http://WayneYe.com

Email: wei.ye@me.com Mobile: +1-415-494-1873 Constellation: Libra



Biography

Veteran full stack engineer/technical lead, certified AWS Solutions Architect, CodeProject MVP, over 17 years' solid experience in a wide range of programming languages/platforms including in C# (ASP.NET), Python (Django/Flask), JavaScript/Nodejs, Ruby (RoR), team player, hard problem solver, with strong expertise and passion in delivering highly available, scalable web/cloud services.

Highlights

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- Author of <Instant Cucumber BDD How-To> (Kindle Version, Google Books)
- CodeProject MVP.
- First prize winner in CodeProject HTML5 & CSS3 Competition, the award was an Ipad 2.

Experience

Sisu Data

Staff Software Engineer

Oct 2021 - Now

Helping Sisu builing industrial leading decision making engine based on KDA (Key Driver Analysis). I worked with PMs, engineering leads in designing/developing service architecture, RESTful APIs, and AWS infra. Using technologies: Python, Rust, Docker/Kubernetes, Snowflake, React.

Autodesk (San Francisco)

Principle Engineer/Technical Lead

Jan 2015 - Oct 2021

Led a development team and built the <u>Autodesk Health Dashboard</u> from scratch, it is the centralized health platform for Autodesk customers around the globe for real time services status/maintenance schedule updates, it monitors 300+ products/micro services, built for accuracy, elesticity and scalability, core technologies including: Python+Django+Flask, React, it runs 100% on AWS (ECS/Lambda 2000+/Aurora/Elasticache(Redis)/DynamoDB/CloudFront, etc).

Other projects I worked on: Autodesk Drive, Autodesk Forge, Autodesk Accounts

Autodesk (Singapore)

Technical Lead

May 2013 - Dec 2014

Led a development team and built <u>Autodesk Developer Platform</u>, it provids a SaaS development portal for Autodesk developers around the globe, technical stacks including Python+Django, Nodejs, C#, MongoDB/Cassandra, Docker, Mesos, ZooKeeper, etc.

ThoughtWorks Shanghai

Software Consultant

May 2012 - Apr 2013

Core Developer of ThoughtWorks China Cloud platform based on OpenStack.

Core Developer of Diamond Subscription website of Real estate Australia, built with Ruby on Rails.

- Server side architecture re-design, delivered proven improved resiliency, maintainability and scalability.
- Improved client page loading performance by leveraging CDN and fingerprint for static files, the average loading time reduced 40%.

SAP Labs Shanghai

Dec 2011 - Apr 2012

Tech Lead

Led a frontend team which prototyped HTML5 client of SAP Business One $\cite{Mathematics}$ OnDemand Control Center.

- Designed JavaScript architecture and built up core framework.
- Defined/implemented RESTful OData web APIs based on WCF.

Hewlett-Packard (PSG - Consumer Experience)

Mar 2009 - Dec 2011

Senior Software Design Engineer/Tech Lead

As a tech lead, I led a development team in Shanghai cooperated with US team on delivering several HP Software Products: <u>HP Total Care Advisor®</u>, <u>HP Customer Experience Enhancement</u>.

Beyondsoft (Onsite to Microsoft) Senior Software Engineer

Jan 2008 - Feb 2009

Worked onsite in Microsoft Redmond Campus on several projects: WM Captaris, MSN Video Catalog Editorial Tool and Visual Studio 2010 MSDN Help Viewer.

Shanghai-Digital Information Technology Co., Ltd ASP/ASP.NET Web Developer

Jul 2005 - Nov 2007

Developed several web projects for Kintera, including: <u>Import Center</u>, Transaction Platform, Financial Link and <u>Single Gift Entry</u>, using technologies including C#, ASP.NET, Ajax, etc.

Motto

No pains, no gains.

Success is 99% Failure.

If you aren't proud of it, it isn't good enough.

High cohesion, lose coupling.

Education Wuhan Jianghan University (2001 - 2005)
Computer Science & Technology